<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>biological data | Yuteng Zhang</title><link>https://Yuteng0927.github.io/tag/biological-data/</link><atom:link href="https://Yuteng0927.github.io/tag/biological-data/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>biological data</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://Yuteng0927.github.io/media/icon_hua2ec155b4296a9c9791d015323e16eb5_11927_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>biological data</title><link>https://Yuteng0927.github.io/tag/biological-data/</link></image><item><title>GUI development for single-molecule fluorescent image processing</title><link>https://Yuteng0927.github.io/project/gui/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://Yuteng0927.github.io/project/gui/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="research-summary">Research Summary&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Single-Molecule Super-Resolution Microscopy (smSRM) is a powerful imaging technique that allows the visualization of cellular structures at a higher resolution, which is widely applied in many fields of study. However, the ability for undergraduate and graduate students to comprehend the smSRM is limited, particularly for beginners who are not familiar with all the biophysical principles behind this technique. To address this, here we created a homemade easy-to-use graphical user interface (GUI) to demonstrate the fundamental concept of smSRM, the fitting of super-resolved images, as well as the significance of key characteristics that would affect the image quality. This user-friendly software makes it intuitive for students to better understand and utilize the smSRM technique, and provides insights into how to design and explore single-molecule super-resolved experiments, and we hope it would inspire more people who are interested in this field to get in touch on this technique.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Single-molecule data processing pipeline</title><link>https://Yuteng0927.github.io/project/data-processing/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://Yuteng0927.github.io/project/data-processing/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="research-summary">Research Summary&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The first step in this process is the localization extraction of individual molecules within the image. This is accomplished by using specialized algorithms that detect the signal emitted from fluorescent markers that are attached to molecules of interest.
The next step is to reconstruct a 2D/3D image from the data obtained in the previous step.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>