<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Projects | Yuteng Zhang</title><link>https://Yuteng0927.github.io/project/</link><atom:link href="https://Yuteng0927.github.io/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Projects</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://Yuteng0927.github.io/media/icon_hua2ec155b4296a9c9791d015323e16eb5_11927_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>Projects</title><link>https://Yuteng0927.github.io/project/</link></image><item><title>Rotten Tomatoes Movies Analysis with Machine Leaning</title><link>https://Yuteng0927.github.io/project/machine-learning/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://Yuteng0927.github.io/project/machine-learning/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="research-summary">Research Summary&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>This project is an analysis of the Rotten Tomatoes Movies dataset, sourced from Kaggle. The dataset contains information about various movies, including ratings, reviews, and other attributes. The analysis was performed using Jupyter Notebook and the Pandas libraries. Exploratory Data Analysis (EDA) techniques were used to examine the data, identify patterns, and extract insights.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Magnetic Maps Inclinations Prediction with Deep Learning</title><link>https://Yuteng0927.github.io/project/deep-learning/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://Yuteng0927.github.io/project/deep-learning/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="research-summary">Research Summary&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>During this project:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>understand the workflow of training a CNN.
use Keras to train a CNN and make predictions.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Web application for Exploring National Parks</title><link>https://Yuteng0927.github.io/project/web-application/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://Yuteng0927.github.io/project/web-application/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="research-summary">Research Summary&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The National Parks project is a web application that allows users to explore national parks across the United States. The application utilizes data from various sources including Kaggle and Data World to provide users with detailed information about each park including its location and activities.The user interface is designed to be user-friendly and easy to navigate, allowing users to filter parks by region and view detailed information about each park. The backend of the application is built using a Flask server and MongoDB to handle data storage and retrieval. This allows for efficient and seamless data retrieval, providing users with the most up-to-date information about the parks.
Overall, the National Parks project is an ideal tool for nature enthusiasts, hikers, and anyone looking to explore and learn more about the national parks of the United States and territories.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>YouTube Data Extraction and Visualization</title><link>https://Yuteng0927.github.io/project/api/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://Yuteng0927.github.io/project/api/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="research-summary">Research Summary&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>This project observed the YouTube&amp;rsquo;s Videos category, counts, likes and comments based per country and its relation to each other. This project answers the question Our analysis focuses on answering below questions: Is there a significant difference in the average like count of the top 50 videos within each designated region within YouTube? Ha:Average like count will be significantly different between the regions H0: There is no difference between the average like count by region&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Is there a significant difference in the average like count of the top 50 videos of each designated category within YouTube? Ha: Average like count will be significantly different between the categories H0: There is no difference between the average like count by category&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Additional Correlations: What is the average percent of videos liked by the number of views they have received?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Project is built to call the YouTube API&amp;rsquo;s dataset related to Video . Due to large size, dataset is saved in CSV file for further analysis(5000 records). Python matplotlib, bar graph, pie charts are used to analyzed the data and specify the correlation in between videos, categories, likes, views and counts. Various methods such a correlation, aggregation, t-test, comparison , ANOVA tests are used to do further analysis of data.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Single-molecule tracking</title><link>https://Yuteng0927.github.io/project/smt/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://Yuteng0927.github.io/project/smt/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="research-summary">Research Summary&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>In this work, we reported a single-molecule tracking approach to study the single-molecule dynamics of nuclear SOD1 in response to oxidative stress in neuron cells. We used H1-SOD1-mEos4b, as our model system, based on CRISPR-Cas9 technique. We have proven that the knock-in cell line was effective based on the sequencing and protein expression analysis of SOD1-mEos4b and we have observed that the engineered homozygous clone that produces SOD1-mEos4b fusion proteins displays typical stem cell morphology. The SOD1 localization and motion was captured by the fluorescent signals emitted from mEos4b and processed for further analysis. The trajectory and diffusion coefficient analysis showed that more SOD1 molecules were immobilized under H2O2 treatment compared to basal condition, which we proposed this could due to more SOD1 binding events happened during the oxidative stress response and therefore slower the nuclear SOD1 diffusion behavior.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>3D single-molecule super-resolution imaging</title><link>https://Yuteng0927.github.io/project/3d_ctr1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://Yuteng0927.github.io/project/3d_ctr1/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="research-summary">Research Summary&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Copper enters human cells through pores formed by trimeric human copper transporter 1 (hCTR1). Elevated Cu induces clathrin-dependent endocytosis of hCTR1 and decreases the hCTR1 surface abundance by half. However, it remains unclear how cells minimize the Cu-uptake activity of the remaining surface hCTR1. This study examined the oligomeric states of hCTR1 complexes in fixed COS7 cells using super-resolution localization microscopy and single-molecule oligomeric state quantification assay. We found that the hCTR1 on the plasma membrane exists dominantly in the trimeric form (~80%) under basal conditions and shifts to monomeric states (~50%) under Cu stressed conditions. This finding suggests cells may further modulate the oligomer distributions of the surface hCTR1 to reduce cellular Cu-uptake and provide insight into the hCTR1 transport mechanism.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>GUI development for single-molecule fluorescent image processing</title><link>https://Yuteng0927.github.io/project/gui/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://Yuteng0927.github.io/project/gui/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="research-summary">Research Summary&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Single-Molecule Super-Resolution Microscopy (smSRM) is a powerful imaging technique that allows the visualization of cellular structures at a higher resolution, which is widely applied in many fields of study. However, the ability for undergraduate and graduate students to comprehend the smSRM is limited, particularly for beginners who are not familiar with all the biophysical principles behind this technique. To address this, here we created a homemade easy-to-use graphical user interface (GUI) to demonstrate the fundamental concept of smSRM, the fitting of super-resolved images, as well as the significance of key characteristics that would affect the image quality. This user-friendly software makes it intuitive for students to better understand and utilize the smSRM technique, and provides insights into how to design and explore single-molecule super-resolved experiments, and we hope it would inspire more people who are interested in this field to get in touch on this technique.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Subcellular antioxidant defense via redox-reactive fluorescent sensor</title><link>https://Yuteng0927.github.io/project/gfp/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://Yuteng0927.github.io/project/gfp/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="project-summary">Project Summary&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>In this work, we reported a new method using combined approaches of organelle-specific redox sensor Grx1-roGFP2 and non-targeted proteomics to investigate the real-time Cu-dependent antioxidant defenses of mitochondria and cytosol in live HEK293 cells. The time-dependent subcellular redox results revealed that subcellular Cu-induced oxidative stress happens with much slower rates and fewer extents than H2O2. Mitochondria appear to have more efficient restoration of Cu-dependent GSH/GSSG ratio than the cytosol. The corresponding proteomics data show that several mitochondrial proteins involved in mitochondrial oxidative phosphorylation and GSH synthesis rapidly undergo significant abundance changes after prolonged Cu treatments. In contrast, cytosolic proteins involved in GSH synthesis undergo substantial changes after Cu reduction. In other words, mitochondria and cytosol have different antioxidant defense mechanisms upon Cu-dependent oxidative stress despite both modulating GSH/GSSG system. Mitochondria respond to Cu treatments and modify protein profiles more significantly than the cytosol. These findings provide information on how redox status changes within cellular compartments and triggers organelle-specific protein abundance changes in response to Cu-level changes, highlighting the interplay mechanisms between redox and Cu homeostasis.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Light sheet imaging</title><link>https://Yuteng0927.github.io/project/ls/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://Yuteng0927.github.io/project/ls/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="project-summary">Project Summary&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>In this work, we implemented a TILT3D setup based on the design presented by &lt;a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-017-02563-4" target="_blank" rel="noopener">W. E. Moerner in 2018&lt;/a>, which by utilizing the strategy of tilted light sheet illumination, namely, by illuminating the sample with a light sheet that is tilted at an angle relative to the imaging plane, to avoid the limitation of early light sheet methods. In the meantime, with the 3D double helix PSF engineering, we built an optimized imaging platform in our lab to achieve high-level single-molecule super-resolution 3D imaging. With this light sheet microscopy combined DH PSF engineering, we reported that the signal-to-noise ratio (SNR) improved significantly compared to conventianl epi-illumination, we are able to study the structure and dynamics of biological molecules at a level of detail that was previously unattainable and provide a valuable tool for advancing our research at single-molecule level.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Single-molecule interaction simulation</title><link>https://Yuteng0927.github.io/project/smis/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://Yuteng0927.github.io/project/smis/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="project-summary">Project Summary&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The ability to extract kinetic interaction parameters from single-molecule fluorescence resonance energy transfer trajectories without the need for solving complex single-molecule differential equations has the potential to address some of the critical biophysical questions. Here, we provide a noise-free single-molecule interaction simulation (SMIS) tool to give the expected dwell-time distributions and relative populations of each FRET level based on the assigned kinetic model and to dissect kinetic interaction parameters from single-molecule FRET trajectories. The method provides the expected dwell-time distributions, average transition rates, and relative populations of each FRET level based on the assigned kinetic model. By comparing with ground truth data and experimental data, we demonstrated that SMIS is useful to quantify the interaction kinetic rate constants without using the traditional single-molecule analytical solution approach.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Single-molecule data processing pipeline</title><link>https://Yuteng0927.github.io/project/data-processing/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://Yuteng0927.github.io/project/data-processing/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="research-summary">Research Summary&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The first step in this process is the localization extraction of individual molecules within the image. This is accomplished by using specialized algorithms that detect the signal emitted from fluorescent markers that are attached to molecules of interest. These algorithms identify the precise location of each molecule, which can then be used to construct a high-resolution image of the sample.
The next step is to reconstruct a three-dimensional (3D) image from the data obtained in the previous step. This requires the use of advanced computational methods to analyze the positions of individual molecules in multiple planes and to generate a 3D model of the sample.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>