<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>single molecule | Yuteng Zhang</title><link>https://Yuteng0927.github.io/tag/single-molecule/</link><atom:link href="https://Yuteng0927.github.io/tag/single-molecule/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>single molecule</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://Yuteng0927.github.io/media/icon_hua2ec155b4296a9c9791d015323e16eb5_11927_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>single molecule</title><link>https://Yuteng0927.github.io/tag/single-molecule/</link></image><item><title>Single-molecule tracking</title><link>https://Yuteng0927.github.io/project/smt/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://Yuteng0927.github.io/project/smt/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="research-summary">Research Summary&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>In this work, we reported a single-molecule tracking approach to study the single-molecule dynamics of nuclear SOD1 in response to oxidative stress in neuron cells. We used H1-SOD1-mEos4b, as our model system, based on CRISPR-Cas9 technique. We have proven that the knock-in cell line was effective based on the sequencing and protein expression analysis of SOD1-mEos4b and we have observed that the engineered homozygous clone that produces SOD1-mEos4b fusion proteins displays typical stem cell morphology. The SOD1 localization and motion was captured by the fluorescent signals emitted from mEos4b and processed for further analysis. The trajectory and diffusion coefficient analysis showed that more SOD1 molecules were immobilized under H2O2 treatment compared to basal condition, which we proposed this could due to more SOD1 binding events happened during the oxidative stress response and therefore slower the nuclear SOD1 diffusion behavior.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>3D single-molecule super-resolution imaging</title><link>https://Yuteng0927.github.io/project/3d_ctr1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://Yuteng0927.github.io/project/3d_ctr1/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="research-summary">Research Summary&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The trimeric human copper transporter 1 (hCTR1) creates pores through which copper can enter human cells. When copper levels are high, hCTR1 is taken into the cell via clathrin-dependent endocytosis, reducing its surface abundance. However, it is not yet known how cells regulate the remaining hCTR1 on the cell surface to prevent excessive copper uptake. To address this question, this study utilized super-resolution localization microscopy and a single-molecule oligomeric state quantification assay to examine the oligomeric states of hCTR1 complexes in fixed COS7 cells.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Subcellular antioxidant defense via redox-reactive fluorescent sensor</title><link>https://Yuteng0927.github.io/project/gfp/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://Yuteng0927.github.io/project/gfp/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="project-summary">Project Summary&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>In this work, we reported a new method using combined approaches of organelle-specific redox sensor Grx1-roGFP2 and non-targeted proteomics to investigate the real-time Cu-dependent antioxidant defenses of mitochondria and cytosol in live HEK293 cells. The time-dependent subcellular redox results revealed that subcellular Cu-induced oxidative stress happens with much slower rates and fewer extents than H2O2. Mitochondria appear to have more efficient restoration of Cu-dependent GSH/GSSG ratio than the cytosol. The corresponding proteomics data show that several mitochondrial proteins involved in mitochondrial oxidative phosphorylation and GSH synthesis rapidly undergo significant abundance changes after prolonged Cu treatments. In contrast, cytosolic proteins involved in GSH synthesis undergo substantial changes after Cu reduction. In other words, mitochondria and cytosol have different antioxidant defense mechanisms upon Cu-dependent oxidative stress despite both modulating GSH/GSSG system. Mitochondria respond to Cu treatments and modify protein profiles more significantly than the cytosol. These findings provide information on how redox status changes within cellular compartments and triggers organelle-specific protein abundance changes in response to Cu-level changes, highlighting the interplay mechanisms between redox and Cu homeostasis.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Light sheet imaging</title><link>https://Yuteng0927.github.io/project/ls/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://Yuteng0927.github.io/project/ls/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="project-summary">Project Summary&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>In this work, we implemented a TILT3D setup based on the design presented by &lt;a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-017-02563-4" target="_blank" rel="noopener">W. E. Moerner in 2018&lt;/a>, which by utilizing the strategy of tilted light sheet illumination, namely, by illuminating the sample with a light sheet that is tilted at an angle relative to the imaging plane, to avoid the limitation of early light sheet methods. In the meantime, with the 3D double helix PSF engineering, we built an optimized imaging platform in our lab to achieve high-level single-molecule super-resolution 3D imaging. With this light sheet microscopy combined DH PSF engineering, we reported that the signal-to-noise ratio (SNR) improved significantly compared to conventianl epi-illumination, we are able to study the structure and dynamics of biological molecules at a level of detail that was previously unattainable and provide a valuable tool for advancing our research at single-molecule level.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Single-molecule interaction simulation</title><link>https://Yuteng0927.github.io/project/smis/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://Yuteng0927.github.io/project/smis/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="project-summary">Project Summary&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The ability to extract kinetic interaction parameters from single-molecule fluorescence resonance energy transfer trajectories without the need for solving complex single-molecule differential equations has the potential to address some of the critical biophysical questions. Here, we provide a noise-free single-molecule interaction simulation (SMIS) tool to give the expected dwell-time distributions and relative populations of each FRET level based on the assigned kinetic model and to dissect kinetic interaction parameters from single-molecule FRET trajectories. The method provides the expected dwell-time distributions, average transition rates, and relative populations of each FRET level based on the assigned kinetic model. By comparing with ground truth data and experimental data, we demonstrated that SMIS is useful to quantify the interaction kinetic rate constants without using the traditional single-molecule analytical solution approach.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>