<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>coding | Yuteng Zhang</title><link>https://Yuteng0927.github.io/tag/coding/</link><atom:link href="https://Yuteng0927.github.io/tag/coding/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>coding</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://Yuteng0927.github.io/media/icon_hua2ec155b4296a9c9791d015323e16eb5_11927_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>coding</title><link>https://Yuteng0927.github.io/tag/coding/</link></image><item><title>Rotten Tomatoes Movies Analysis with Machine Leaning</title><link>https://Yuteng0927.github.io/project/machine-learning/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://Yuteng0927.github.io/project/machine-learning/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="research-summary">Research Summary&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>This project is an analysis of the Rotten Tomatoes Movies dataset, sourced from Kaggle. The dataset contains information about various movies, including ratings, reviews, and other attributes. The analysis was performed using Jupyter Notebook and the Pandas libraries. Exploratory Data Analysis (EDA) techniques were used to examine the data, identify patterns, and extract insights.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Magnetic Maps Inclinations Prediction with Deep Learning</title><link>https://Yuteng0927.github.io/project/deep-learning/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://Yuteng0927.github.io/project/deep-learning/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="research-summary">Research Summary&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>During this project:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>understand the workflow of training a CNN.
use Keras to train a CNN and make predictions.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Web application for Exploring National Parks</title><link>https://Yuteng0927.github.io/project/web-application/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://Yuteng0927.github.io/project/web-application/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="research-summary">Research Summary&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The National Parks project is a web application that allows users to explore national parks across the United States. The application utilizes data from various sources including Kaggle and Data World to provide users with detailed information about each park including its location and activities.The user interface is designed to be user-friendly and easy to navigate, allowing users to filter parks by region and view detailed information about each park. The backend of the application is built using a Flask server and MongoDB to handle data storage and retrieval. This allows for efficient and seamless data retrieval, providing users with the most up-to-date information about the parks.
Overall, the National Parks project is an ideal tool for nature enthusiasts, hikers, and anyone looking to explore and learn more about the national parks of the United States and territories.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>YouTube Data Extraction and Visualization</title><link>https://Yuteng0927.github.io/project/api/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://Yuteng0927.github.io/project/api/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="research-summary">Research Summary&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>This project observed the YouTube&amp;rsquo;s Videos category, counts, likes and comments based per country and its relation to each other. This project answers the question Our analysis focuses on answering below questions: Is there a significant difference in the average like count of the top 50 videos within each designated region within YouTube? Ha:Average like count will be significantly different between the regions H0: There is no difference between the average like count by region&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Is there a significant difference in the average like count of the top 50 videos of each designated category within YouTube? Ha: Average like count will be significantly different between the categories H0: There is no difference between the average like count by category&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Additional Correlations: What is the average percent of videos liked by the number of views they have received?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Project is built to call the YouTube API&amp;rsquo;s dataset related to Video . Due to large size, dataset is saved in CSV file for further analysis(5000 records). Python matplotlib, bar graph, pie charts are used to analyzed the data and specify the correlation in between videos, categories, likes, views and counts. Various methods such a correlation, aggregation, t-test, comparison , ANOVA tests are used to do further analysis of data.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>